630 Parthenon Pl

New Caney, TX

Sean Daniel Davis <u>s.davis@tamu.edu</u> 214-799-7708

Texas A&M University 400 Bizzell St College Station, TX

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

After college I hope to change the standards of the A/V industry by making educated consumers, bringing great media experiences to all price points, and providing easy-to-use software to control large scale media projects. I would love to travel around the nation and interact with companies and cultures around the world. I am driven to accomplish my goals and strive to surpass people's expectations of me. My favorite job experience has been teaching people and helping to solve practical problems within my community.

#### **EDUCATION**

Texas A&M University (3.825) College Station, TX

Computer Science, m. Cyber Security 05/2023

Stephen F. Austin High School (3.76)

Graduated Summa Cum Laude

Sugarland, TX

05/2019

Top 10% of graduating class with honors

#### **COURSEWORK**

- Analysis of Algorithms (C++)
- Computer Systems
- Programming Studio (Python, CSS, JS, HTML, PHP, MySQL)
- Data Structures (C++)

- Discrete Structures and Mathematics
- Programming Languages (Scheme, Java)
- Computer Organization(HDL,ASM)

#### **SKILL SET**

#### **Technical Skills**

- Audio Installation
- C++

• CSS

Sound Mixing

• Java

JavaScript

Broadcast
 Networking

Python

HTML

### **Professional Skills**

- Team Management, Teaching, and Interpersonal Communication
- Debugging, Troubleshooting, and Code Review

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Telemundo Houston | KTMD** Dec 2020 – January 2021

Computer Engineer / IT Intern 40 hours

- Upgraded chipsets in news cameras
- Designed/installed a server rack with audio, visuals, and editing in a remote broadcast truck
- Maintain servers and software for news broadcast, including systems used by 40 instation editors and managers (Unity, Stratus editing, KVM, Dejero encode/decode)

• Maintained and deployed new technology to associates including cellular phones, laptops, TV station cameras, video encoding boxes

## Texas A&M University July 2020 – Present

Teaching Assistant for Discrete Structures 10 hours

- Taught and assisted engineering students through one on one sessions to understand Discrete Structure and Analysis of algorithms
- Developed a higher level of understanding of analysis of algorithms through peer teaching

## **Home Depot** April 2020 – August 2020

Deliveries Associate

- Prepared and delivered 10 deliveries of lumber and concrete onto delivery trucks from the warehouse every day
- Interacted with and grew personable skills with customers in customer service center

#### **KEY PROJECTS**

TV Station Equipment Upgrade – Telemundo Inc.

- Installed chipsets into all new station cameras allowing them to store video and be used by emergency first responders for quicker broadcast
- Deployed new phones, connecting 28 field reporters to the corporate network, equipped with faster data chips and more reliable internet connection for emergency broadcasts

**A/V Installation** – Brian Consolidated

- Installed and tested 3 sound systems for different high school graduation ceremonies
- Ran live sound at event and learned audio mixing and effects

**Live Worship Setup** – *Antioch Community Church* 

- Set up a portable live band stage for various worship nights in Bryan/College Station
- Ran live sound mixing and communication with music director from the stage

Music Production – Personal Music Recording

- Produced 3 fleshed-out songs at home during quarantine
- Used many free and payed effects plugins and discovered a zeal for making my own in a future project

#### **ACTIVITIES AND HONORS**

Engineering Team Lead – Intro to Engineering 2019

- Served as a project lead for a Python based video game with 4 developers
- Developed a video game closely resembling popular Japanese RPG "Pokémon"

**Drum Major** – Austin High School Band 2019

- Represented a band of 140 students at national conferences and competitions
- Taught students' intricate styles of marching and formations, as well as directing musical compositions

#### REFERENCES

**Philip Muller** – Supervising Manager at KTMD Telemundo Houston

• (281)-684-8678

**Melanio Polanco** – Co-worker at KTMD Telemundo Houston

• (832)-306-8821

**Jonathan Stone** – Sound Engineer at Antioch Community Church

• (979)-324-0361